-早安  -嗨
- Morning. - Hi.
昨晚约会还顺利吗
How was your date?
-很不错  -太好了
- Pretty good. - Oh, good.
天啊  抱歉
My God. Sorry about that.
好吧  非常好
Okay, really good.
我要走了  上班要迟到了
I gotta go. I'm late for work.
你要把她丢给我
You're going to leave this person with me?
别担心  她人很好
Don't worry, she's a terrific girl.
你能帮我一个忙吗
Can you do me a favor?
你能跟她提一下
Could you mention I'm not
我没打算定下来吗  谢谢了
looking for a relationship? That'd be great.
什么  你在开玩笑吗
What, are you kidding?
就轻描淡写地不经意提一下
Just casually slip it in, you know. Lay the groundwork.
说我从来独来独往  不  是亡命之徒
Tell her I'm a loner. No, an outlaw.
她不会想跟我这种人混在一起的
She doesn't want to get mixed up with the likes of me.
太多了记不住
That's a lot to remember.
我不能直接告诉她你是猪吗
Can't I tell her that you're a pig?
我过会自己给她打电话
I'm gonna call her later myself.
保证打
Honest.
过去都是钱德勒搞定  他会给她做煎饼
Chandler used to do it. He'd make her pancakes.
他会多做几块留给我吃
He'd make extras and leave them for me.
我什么都不会说的  这不是我的责任
I'm not telling her anything. It's not my responsibility.
行吧
Fine.
那煎饼谁吃啊
Now, where did we land on those pancakes?
-嗨  -嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
抱歉  但是我锁不上门
Sorry, but I couldn't get that lock to work.
乔伊在我搬进来的时候  把锁弄坏了
Yeah, Joey kind of disabled it when I moved in.
-你肯定就是瑞秋了我是艾琳  -嗨
- You must be Rachel. I'm Erin. - Hi.
我不想跟高中女生一样无聊
I don't mean this to sound like high school,
但他有跟你谈到我吗
but did he talk about me?
字幕
Would you like some pancakes?
-我们来这干嘛  -猜一下嘛
- Come on. Why are we here? - Okay, okay, take a guess.
这里有辣妹
The hot chicks?
我之前在图书馆里的电脑上
Okay, okay, I was typing names
输入人名来着
into the library computer earlier...
就是好玩
...you know, for fun.
我输入我的名字  你猜我发现了什么
And I typed mine in, and guess what came up.
我的博士论文
My doctoral dissertation.
就在大学里最大的图书馆里
It's right down here in the biggest library in the university.
那真的很酷
Wow, that's actually pretty cool.
还有一本温迪·巴继娜写的书
There's also a book here by a woman named Wendy Bagina.
那是什么
What is that?
听起来像是两个
Sounds like two people are
非常享受杜威十进制系统的人
really enjoying the Dewey Decimal System.
太抱歉了
We're so sorry.
你不会是带我来这里做那档子事的对吧
You didn't bring me here to do that, did you?
她又把鸡肉退回来了吗
She sent the chicken back again?
她说鸡肉大干
She said it's too dry and
想亲自跟你解释她要什么样的鸡肉
wants to explain to you how she wants it.
我倒想会会这位鸡肉专家
Well fine. I'd like to meet this chicken expert.
传上校[暗指肯德基的创始人]进来吧
Send the colonel in.
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
躲过一劫的混蛋
Lucky bastard.
-珍妮丝  -你怎么样啊
- Janice. - How are you...
高级大餐厅里处理上等鸡肉的辣妹大厨师
Ms. Hotshot-Chef-at-the-Big-Fancy- Restaurant-With-the-Best-Chicken-Ever?
我挺好
I'm fine.
你手上戴了什么  晃瞎我的眼了
Oh, what is that on your finger? I'm blind.
是哪个幸运的男人
So who's the lucky guy?
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
我真的很抱歉  甜心
I am so sorry, sweetie.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
你没告诉她我们订婚了吧
You didn't tell her we're engaged?
-她看到戒指了  -她疯了吧
- She saw the ring. - Did she freak out?
她很震惊  之后就和大家反应一样了
She was shocked, but then again, so were most people.
她有男朋友了
She actually has a boyfriend herself.
叫克拉克
Name's Clark.
她还自说自话说她要参加我们的婚礼
She also invited herself to our wedding.
克拉克也要来
Clark too.
你拒绝了对吧
You said no, right?
她把我逼得没有办法  问我是不是在纽约办
She cornered me. She asked me if the wedding was in town.
-我该怎么办  -骗子
- What was I supposed to do? - Lie.
能有多难啊  "给你的支票寄出去了"
How hard is that? "Your check's in the mail."
"你家小孩真可爱"
"Oh, your baby's so cute."
"简直等不及要读你的书了  罗斯"
"I can't wait to read your book, Ross."
就让她来嘛  说不定没那么糟糕呢
So she comes to the wedding. Maybe it won't be so bad.
你以为她会安静坐着   会跟我们举杯致意
Think she'll sit quietly? Think she'll want to make a toast?
你不会还以为她会唱《兼职情人》吧
You don't think she'll grab the microphone and sing "Part-Time Lover"?
她也不会喜欢婚礼上的鸡肉的
Oh, my God. She's not gonna like the chicken either, is she?
应该没事
You know what? It'll be okay.
她也许都不会现身
She's probably not gonna even want to come.
-真的  -不  我骗你呢
- Really? - No, that was a lie.
看  说谎有多容易
See how easy that was?
所以你能轻易说谎
So you would have just lied?
对
Yes.
-对你来说很容易  -对
- It would have really been that easy? - Yes.
那就周六晚上撒谎吧
Do it on Saturday night.
我们要和她还有克拉克吃饭
We're having dinner with her and Clark.
还好吗
Hey, what's up?
介绍一下你的朋友吧
Hey, who's your friend?
-嗨乔伊  -艾琳
- Hey, Joey. - Erin.
你还在啊
You're still here.
我们在一起一整天  玩得很开心
We ended up spending the day together and had such a great time.
当然了  艾琳可棒了
Why wouldn't you? Erin is great.
当然还有你们
And then there's you guys.
我得走了
Well, listen, I better get going.
我今天很高兴  谢谢
Today was great. Thanks.
乔伊  昨晚真的很棒
And, Joey, last night was fun.
我再打给你
Yeah. I'll call you.
-我也会打给你  -或者打给你
- I'll call you too. - Or I'll call you.
-记得打给我  -好
- And call me. - Okay.
再见到你很高兴
Good to see you again.
-再见  -再见
- Bye-bye. - Bye.
赶走她的系统出故障了吗
The system kind of broke down, huh?
乔伊  抱歉我真的开不了口
Joey, I'm sorry. I just couldn't tell her all those things.
我们开始聊起天来  我
And we got to talking, and I...
我们要你娶她
We want you to marry her.
什么
What?
你都不知道她有多棒
She is so amazing. You have no idea.
那是谁把她带到这里的呢
Who do you think brought her here?
丘比特
Cupid.
她太酷了  会说4门语言
She's so cool. She speaks four languages.
天  你还真了解男人需求
Man, do you know what guys want.
她跟你是天生一对  她真的很漂亮
Come on, she's so perfect for you. She's sweet.
她喜欢棒球  午餐时还喝了两瓶啤酒
She likes baseball. She had two beers at lunch.
我的啤酒
My beers?!
她真的是个好女孩
Look, she's a very nice girl.
我们相处甚欢 但我不觉得我们会有结局
We had a very good time, but I don't see it going anywhere.
你老那么说
You always say that.
也许你给她个机会  就会不一样呢
Maybe if you gave her a chance, it would go somewhere.
抱歉  我不这么想
I'm sorry, you guys. I just don't think so.
-随便  -好吧
- Whatever. - Fine.
别戴有色眼镜看我
Hey, don't start judging me.
你暗恋你的助理
You're in love with your assistant.
而你和在房顶上养鸽子的男人
You're having an affair
搞外遇
with the guy who keeps pigeons on the roof.
菲比
Phoebe!
秘密恋爱而已
Secret affair.
有人在我的书前嘿咻
People are doing it in front of my book.
你说什么
I'm sorry?
我的博士论文
My doctoral dissertation
就在学校图书馆  我去看
is in the library at school. I went to see it.
结果有俩学生
And there were students
就在古生物学区造人呢
making babies right in the paleontology section.
天啊  你有看到什么好料吗
Oh, my God. Did you get to see anything good?
在你们学校
At your school...
有没有什么地方
...was there a place on campus
是你们学生用来鬼混的
where students went to fool around?
有啊
Yeah, there was.
就在图书馆一隅
In the corner of the library
堆着那些从落满灰尘的没人看的书的地方
where all the dusty books were that nobody ever read.
有的
Yes, there was.
因为人们就不停地出现  好像有什么约定一样
Great, because people kept showing up. I think it's like a thing.
慢着
Hold on a second.
第五层  那堵黑墙前面
Fifth floor, against that back wall?
我的天啊
Oh, for crying out loud!
-我们该动身去看电影了  -干嘛这么急
- So we should go catch our movie. - What's the rush?
我想看预告片
I like to see the previews.
有糖果拿
The candy.
-嗨  -看谁来了
- Oh, hey. - Well, look who's here.
-嗨乔伊  -嗨艾琳
- Hey, Joey. - Hey, Erin.
-嗨瑞秋  -嗨
- Hey, Rachel. - Hi.
我们准备去看电影
We were about to take off and see a movie.
-哦不  -怎么了
- Oh, no! - What's wrong?
菲比  我们不是要参加那个派对吗
Phoebe, we forgot that party we have to go to.
不
Oh, no.
哪个派对
What party?
-生日派对  -生日派对
- A birthday party. - A birthday party.
谁的生日
Whose birthday party?
-艾莉森的生日派对  -艾莉森的
- Alison's birthday party. - Alison's birthday party.
艾莉森几岁
And how old is Alison?
-32  -32
- Thirty-two. - Thirty-two.
慢着  你们俩干嘛不一起呢
Wait a minute. Why don't you guys do something?
看看会怎样
Look how that worked out.
抱歉  我是教授
Excuse me. Hi, I'm a professor here.
你知道古生物区  5楼  437书架
Do you know the paleontology section, fifth floor, stack 437?
知道  给我5分钟
Well, yes. Just give me five minutes.
我得找人来帮我代班
I just have to find someone to cover my shift.
不不不
No, no, no.
我能和你们管事的谈一下吗
Can I speak to someone in charge?
有什么事吗
How can I help?
你好  我想问馆方能不能增加人手
Hi, I was wondering, is it possible to increase security...
巡逻古生物学区
...in the paleontology section?
我写的书放在那里
I wrote a book that's up there.
但大家去那里不是看书  而是
And instead of reading it, people are...
他们在我的书面前打滚
Well, they're rolling around in front of it.
你反应的问题我们知道
We are aware of the problem you're referring to.
但增加巡逻这件事
As far as increasing security,
恐怕馆方的人力不足
I'm afraid the library's understaffed.
我帮不上你的忙
I can't help you.
好吧
Well, fine.
如果我是唯一愿意欣赏
If I'm the only person with any appreciation...
文字之美的人
...of the sanctity of the written word,
我会亲自去捍卫它
then I'll go defend it myself.
别跟着我
Don't you follow me.
-和艾琳进展顺利吗  -不可思议
- How did it go with Erin? - Unbelievable.
最好的时光
We had the best time.
你不再生我们气啦
So you're not mad at us anymore?
你们说的都对
No, no. You guys were totally right.
这次比第一次约会好多了
This was much better than the first date.
之前非常尴尬  我们都很紧张
That was awkward. We were both nervous.
-你们不是睡了吗  -那才让我冷静下来
- didn't you sleep together? - Yeah, that calms me down.
我们有太多共同点
And we have so much in common.
她喜欢三明治和运动  但她是大都会队的球迷
She loves sandwiches, sports. Although she is a Met fan.
现在都不是问题了  但如果我们有了孩子
Not an issue now, but if we had kids...
你竟然会提到生孩子的事
Oh, my God! Listen to you talking about having kids.
我的乔伊
Oh, my Joey.
别比我先结婚
Please don't get married before I do.
我不敢相信克拉克会放我鸽子
I just cannot believe that Clark stood me up.
他应该会来
He may still show up.
你是笨蛋吗
What are you, stupid?
-我们已经等了三小时  -只有三小时吗
- It's been three hours. - Is that all?
说些高兴的
Let's go on to happier things.
谈谈你们的婚礼
Why don't you tell me about your lovely wedding.
关于婚礼  我们有事要跟你说
There was something that we wanted to tell you about the wedding.
仪式会很低调
It's going to be a small ceremony.
很小
Tiny.
我们都不一定办
We're not even sure why we're having it.
只有家人会参加
It's actually going to be just family.
慢着
Oh, wait.
你们把我当家人
You two think of me as family?
我必须得问问你  实际上
I have to ask you something now, and be honest.
你希望我唱《无心低语》还是《红衣女郎》
Do you want me to sing "Careless Whisper" Or "Lady in Red"?
你怎么能这么说呢  大都市队没有好投手
How can you say that? The Mets have no closer.
-班尼提兹呢   -第一场比赛呢
- What about Benitez? - What about game one of the series?
-你闭嘴吧  -你才闭嘴
- What about shut up? - You shut up.
我喜欢和她争论
I love arguing with her.
-马上回来  -好
- Be right back. - Okay.
和乔伊怎么样
How's it going with Joey?
还好
Oh, okay.
Okay?
告诉我你喜欢他
Tell me that you like him, please.
I mean, tell me that you like him.
他人很好
He's a really great guy,
我也知道你们很希望我们能合得来
and I know you really want this to work out...
但我没觉得这事有未来
...but I just don't see this having a future.
但你说你喜欢他的  怎么了
But you said that you liked him. What happened?
改变心意了吗
Did you just change your mind?
-有点  -那就改回来
- Kind of. - Then change it back!
对不起  我们之间真的没有火花
I'm sorry. It's just, there's no real spark.
你们不是滚床单了吗
didn't you sleep together?
是啊
Yeah.
荡妇
Tramp.
乔伊知道吗
Does Joey have any idea?
我觉得他不知道
I don't think he does. You know what?
也许你们能帮我告诉他
Maybe you could tell him I'm not interested...
我没打算定下来之类的
...in a serious relationship.
类似于你总是独来独往之类的
You mean, like, that you're kind of a loner?
那就最好不过了
Yeah, that'd be great.
-也许说你是个混蛋  -抱歉
- And maybe that you're a real stronzo. - I'm sorry?
看来你会说的四门外语里不包括意大利语
I guess Italian isn't one of the four languages you speak.
-想走吗  -走吧
- Hey. Want to go? - Yeah, let's go.
-一会见  -再见
- Okay. See you guys later. - Bye, guys.
太感谢你们了
Hey, thank you so much.
我猜不是丘比特带她来的
I guess it wasn't Cupid that brought her here.
就是个普通的聋子飞行小矮人
No, just a regular old flying dwarf.
怎么了   需要我帮忙吗
Yes, yes? How can I help you?
我们只是四处看看
We were just looking around.
哦  学者啊
Oh, you're fellow scholars.
你们在找什么
What exactly were you looking for?
或许你们想看查斯特·史塔克博士的
Perhaps Dr. Chester Stock's musings...
封剑齿虎的研究
...on the Smilodon californicus?
快滚
Get out of here!
你来找人吗
Meeting someone?
还是你想来看看
Or are you just here to brush up...
玛莉安对进化论的看法
...on Merriam's views on evolution?
事实上  我觉得玛莉安的观点太激进了
Actually, I find Merriam's views far too progressionist.
我也觉得玛莉安的观点太激进了
I find Merriam's views far too progressionist.
不好意思  你是
I'm sorry. Who are you?
我是这里的教授  罗斯·盖勒
I'm a professor here. Ross Geller.
罗斯·盖勒  我怎么会丢这个名字有印象
Ross Geller? Why do I know that name? It's a...
等下
Wait.
这是你写的
Did you write this?
对
Yes.
你是看了我的书的人
You're the person who checked out my book?
你和我想象的一点都不像
You know, you look nothing like I would have thought.
如此年轻
You're so young.
我3年级的时候跳级了
Well, I skipped fourth grade.
真是太抱歉了
I am very, very sorry.
你们的约会还顺利吗
So how was your date?
太棒了  我们在格林威治村散步
Great. We walked around the Village.
还去了冰淇淋店一起喝一杯奶昔
We went to this ice-cream place. Split a milk shake.
我喝的比较多  但还是很棒
Seventy-thirty, but still.
我想带她到北区宾馆去过一夜
I'm thinking of taking her upstate
然后早上在床上吃早餐什么的
to one of those bed and breakfasts.
真的吗   她答应了吗
Really? She said she wants to go?
是惊喜
No, it's a surprise.
时间难搭配  因为她的工作很忙
It's gonna be tricky because she's busy at work.
甜心  乔伊  我们得谈一谈
Okay, honey. Joey, we need to talk, okay?
她让我觉得
I got the feeling from her...
她没打算定下来
...that she's not looking for a serious relationship.
-你怎么看出来的  -她告诉我的
- Where are you getting this? - She told me.
她说她向来独来独往
She said she's kind of a loner.
-乔伊  -瑞秋没事的
- Joey... - Hey, Rach, it's cool, you know.
我也都是独来独往的
I'm a loner too, right?
乔伊  她配不上你
Hey, Joey. You know what? You are way too good for her.
我发誓 下次我会告诉她们
I promise, next time I will tell them
你不想定下来
you're not looking for a relationship.
别  只要
No, don't do that. Just...
-下一次确定她喜欢我  -我会的
- Next time, make sure she likes me. - Well, that too.
乔伊
Joey?
-想吃煎饼吗  -终于啊
- Do you want some pancakes? - Finally.
我们该怎么办
What are we gonna do?
我们该选《无心低语》
I say we go with "Careless Whisper."
钱德勒
Chandler?
她看到我们了吗
Did she see us yet? Did she see us?
珍妮丝  你来这里做什么
Janice, what are you doing here?
我想回我家去
I thought I was gonna go back to my apartment...
但我觉得今晚我不想独处
...but I just felt like I really couldn't be alone tonight.
我在想或许我可以待在你们家
I was just wondering if I could maybe stay here with you.
我真的觉得我该跟家人在一起
Just, I really feel like I need to be with family.
我们的孩子会叫她珍妮丝阿姨  对吧
Our kids are gonna call her Aunt Janice, aren't they?
拜托  否则我真的不知道自己会不会做傻事
Please. Because otherwise, I really don't know what I might do.
你不会有点好奇吗
Aren't you just a teensy bit curious?
-你有面纸吗   -有  在浴室里
- Do you have any tissues? - Yeah, in the bathroom.
我们得收留她
We'll just let her stay.
不  如果我们收留她她会永远住在这里
No. If we let her stay, she will stay forever.
和你的躺椅一样
Kind of like your Barcalounger.
你现在真的在想这个吗
Is that what you're thinking about right now?
我一直都在想
I never stop thinking about it.
伙计们
Hey, you guys?
我洗澡前  你们有人要用浴室吗
Do either one of you want to get in there before I take my bath?
珍妮丝  我很抱歉
Janice, I'm sorry...
但是今晚你不能留在这
...but you can't stay here tonight.
为什么
Why not?
说实话吗
Honestly?
我们家因为电磁辐射的关系
Our apartment is a hotbed...
遭到了污染
...for electromagnetic activity.
莫妮卡跟我已经免疫了  但不幸地
Monica and I have been immunized, but sadly...
你没有免疫力
...you have not.
我需要一条棉被
I'm gonna need a comforter.
你有抗过敏的棉被吗
Do you have a hypoallergenic one?
否则我鼻子灰过敏
Because otherwise I get very nasal.
你们养了猫吗   因为我已经开始过敏了
Do you have a cat? Because it's already happening.
你们听到了吗   你们听
Do you hear that? Listen.
我的天啊  你非离开不可
Oh, my God! Oh, my God! You have to go.
为什么
Why?
因为钱德勒对你还有感觉
Because Chandler still has feelings for you.
是吗
He does?
再说一次
Say again?
对  对
That's right. That's right.
所以你不能留下
And that is why you can't stay here tonight.
你也不应该参加我们的婚礼
And probably why you shouldn't come to the wedding.
感觉  他对你还有感觉
Feelings. Such strong feelings.
我懂
I mean, I realize that
他对你的感觉可能永远不会消失
his feelings may never completely go away...
但是你可以
...but you can.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
我理解  对不起
I understand. I am so sorry.
我走
I'll go.
再见  莫妮卡
Goodbye, Monica.
希望你们白头偕老
I wish you a lifetime of happiness with him.
钱德勒
Chandler.
和丫离婚的时候给我打电话
You call me when this goes in the pooper.
别紧张  这一区有我
Don't sweated, I got this section covered.
事实上  我搞了这么一个小手电照人眼睛
Yeah, in fact, I've got this baby to shine in people's eye...
再见啦
Okay, see you later.
我只是想给莫妮卡看看你的书
I just wanted to show Monica your book.